{
  "css": [
    {
      "question": "qwerty",
      "answers": ["a1", "a2", "a3", "a4"],
      "correct": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "CSS is?",
      "answers": [
        "Programming Language",
        "Hypertext Markup Language",
        "Cascading Style Sheet",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "correct": 2,
      "explanation": "Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) is a style sheet language used for specifying the presentation and styling of a document written in a markup language such as HTML or XML"
    },
    {
      "question": "CSS is?",
      "answers": ["safd", "asdf", "saf", "sdfa"],
      "correct": 2,
      "explanation": "css is a cascading style sheet which helps in styling html and xml files on browser.\n\nExample:\n```\n.p {\n   color: yellow;\n   font-size: 34px;\n}\n```"
    },
    {
      "question": "which one is flex box item property?",
      "answers": ["vvzxbdgs", "gsddgs", "sdgfdgsdg", "nxcvbcvx"],
      "correct": 1,
      "explanation": "cvCdzfcsdfvzxvdsgecxzvsgevzxcdfsadegvd\n\n```\n xczvxczv xzvbxvbxvxzx\n    gsgdgdfgsd\n```"
    },
    {
      "question": "CSS isa a? ",
      "answers": ["asfdsa", "sdfsf", "asdfas", "fasdf"],
      "correct": 2,
      "code": "[data-theme=\"dark\"] pre code {\n  background: #2c2c2c;\n  color: #f8f8f8;\n}\n\n[data-theme=\"dark\"] form {\n  background-color: #2a2a2a;\n  color: #f1f1f1;\n  box-shadow: 0 0 10px rgba(255, 255, 255, 0.05);\n}\n\n[data-theme=\"dark\"] pre code {\n  background: #2c2c2c;\n  color: #f8f8f8;\n}\n\n[data-theme=\"dark\"] form {\n  background-color: #2a2a2a;\n  color: #f1f1f1;\n  box-shadow: 0 0 10px rgba(255, 255, 255, 0.05);\n}\n\n\n[data-theme=\"dark\"] pre code {\n  background: #2c2c2c;\n  color: #f8f8f8;\n}\n\n[data-theme=\"dark\"] form {\n  background-color: #2a2a2a;\n  color: #f1f1f1;\n  box-shadow: 0 0 10px rgba(255, 255, 255, 0.05);\n}\n\n\n[data-theme=\"dark\"] pre code {\n  background: #2c2c2c;\n  color: #f8f8f8;\n}\n\n[data-theme=\"dark\"] form {\n  background-color: #2a2a2a;\n  color: #f1f1f1;\n  box-shadow: 0 0 10px rgba(255, 255, 255, 0.05);\n}",
      "explanation": "safasdfsda\n```\n[data-theme=\"dark\"] pre code {\n  background: #2c2c2c;\n  color: #f8f8f8;\n}\n\n[data-theme=\"dark\"] form {\n  background-color: #2a2a2a;\n  color: #f1f1f1;\n  box-shadow: 0 0 10px rgba(255, 255, 255, 0.05);\n}\n```"
    }
  ],
  "python": [
    {
      "question": "which one is not used in python?",
      "answers": ["br", "if", "while", "for"],
      "correct": 0
    },
    {
      "question": "python is ? which one is not correct?",
      "answers": [
        "programming language",
        "can be used for automation",
        "Hypertext Markup Language",
        "none of these"
      ],
      "correct": 2
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a correct syntax to output \"Hello World\" in Python?",
      "answers": [
        "echo \"Hello World!\"",
        "p(\"Hello World!\")",
        "print(\"Hello World!\")",
        "echo(\"Hello World!\")"
      ],
      "correct": 2,
      "explanation": "abc"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is python?",
      "answers": [
        "Hypertext Markup Language",
        "Programming Language",
        "Cascading Style Sheet",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "correct": 1,
      "explanation": "Python is a high-level, general-purpose programming language designed for code readability, with a syntax that emphasizes the use of significant whitespace.\n\n\n```\nname = \"John\"\nage = 56\n\nprint(f\"{name=}, {age=}\")\n```"
    }
  ],
  "bash": [
    {
      "question": "which one is not from bash syntax?",
      "answers": ["if", "read", "echo", "p tag"],
      "correct": 3,
      "code": "if: {\n----\n}\nelse{\n---\n}\nfi",
      "explanation": "p tag: It is a HTML tag. Paragraph tag <p></p>"
    }
  ],
  "javascript": [
    {
      "question": "javascript is used mostly used on browsers:",
      "answers": ["yes", "no", "50-50", "i don't know"],
      "correct": 0
    }
  ],
  "html": [
    {
      "question": "aljklfjsd",
      "answers": ["jklfjals", "asdfsdaf", "asfdsadfdas"],
      "correct": 0,
      "code": "lkjasjlfafj",
      "explanation": "dsafsdaf\n```\n\ngafdsafsdf\n\n```"
    }
  ]
}
